Right now, you have really developed a lot of programming skills, and I'm thrilled to see the progress
you've made.
Now we're going to embark on a new adventure, as programming is often an adventure of twists and turns,
getting lost and then finding your way.
It's much like a navigating through a dense forest, but eventually you find a way to the clearing where
the beauty of your creation awaits you.
That's it for our next programming adventure.
We will rarely be leveling up your skills by creating a much more complex and dynamic game.
This game is an endless traffic runner game where you are a car and you're speeding along a highway.
This game will challenge your programming skills, but it'll also be a lot of fun.
So before we dive into importing sprites and designing the game, let's first take a step back and understand
the bigger picture.
When building a game.
As I've said, it's crucial to break down the project into smaller, achievable steps, and this becomes
even more important the more complex a project becomes.
That said, in our endless traffic running game, we'll be building the following components the player
car, the trees on each side of the road, the road lines, the obstacle course and the road backdrop.
Now let's take a look at why we need these sprites and how they will contribute to our game.
Firstly, the player's car sprite will be the main character that the user controls, dodging obstacles
and navigating through the traffic.
Then, the tree sprites create a visually appealing environment and help set the scene for our game.
So while we're driving, it'll appear like we are passing trees and other plants and rocks.
The road lines are all about providing a sense of motion or the illusion of motion, because obviously
our car can't move forward, will go off the top of the screen so we can make it look like it is going
forward with the road sprite.
The obstacle course.
Spratt will be the challenge of our game.
It's what the player must avoid to keep their run going.
And finally the road backdrop sets the stage for a game, immersing the player in the world that we've
created.
Now that we have a clear understanding of the components needed for our game, let's start importing
our assets.
Now, this will be our first time importing sprite assets from our computer.
But don't worry, it's a simple process.
And before we continue, as mentioned before, you have a choice here.
You have two different types of assets to choose from.
Either you can download the raw assets which will be all the different images, sounds, music, etc.
and follow along as we show you how to import and edit them.
And this will give you some experience working with the graphics.
Or if you just want to focus on the coding side of things, you can download the project asset which
will have all the sprites, music and sound effects are ready to go, but personally, I do encourage
you to follow along with the raw assets as this will give you some great experience.
So first things first, let's create our brand new project and like all the times before we can just
click select this create button.
And if at this stage you want to use the preloaded project, simply click here, then load from your
computer, then move over to our Starter Traffic Runner project file.
But let's look at the proper way now.
Firstly, let's delete the cat sprite where we don't need.
So the next thing we need to do is upload our sprite like before.
Move over to this button but don't click it.
Instead, we can select this button right at the top that says Upload Sprite.
So the first sprite we want to upload is our player car sprite.
So moving over to the Project assets folder here you will see our Traffic Runner folder.
And if you click on that you will see that we have a folder for each of our sprites.
So selecting our player sprite here you can choose whatever car you want for your player sprite.
I will select this one here and hit open.
And do you have it?
Our player sprite is now in our project and ready to go.
But let's not stop there.
Let's upload our other sprite.
So like before, just click upload and this time we can select the obstacle course sprite.
And here it doesn't matter which one you select as we'll use all of them.
So we can select open.
And before we move to our next sprite, we need to upload our other core obstacle sprites.
And you may be thinking that we will just have a bunch of different obstacle sprites here, but we will
do something a bit more clever than that.
Moving on to the costumes for this cosplay.
Here we can again click upload and this time we can select all the other cars simply by clicking this
car.
Holding down shift and clicking the last car.
And there you have it.
All our cars are in one.
Fancy that.
So let's move on to our next sprite and again clicking upload.
This time we can select our tree and foliage sprite.
So just like with our car sprite, we can just select the first one, then hit open.
Then moving over to the costume editor, we can click this button here.
And then once again we can select all these other costumes and hit upload.
And there you go.
So now there's just one more sprite.
So hitting upload and this time we can select this road lane sprite here and click open.
So that's all our sprite.
We just now need to upload our backdrop.
So simply clicking on it, clicking backdrops and then upload.
And here we can choose this backdrop image here and click open.
And that's just about it.
We have all our sprites ready to go so get ready for it.
But but great work so far as we have all our sprites uploaded.
We have completed our first stage of game development, and you also have a good idea of the bigger
picture of the game and why we have all the sprites we have.